District of Columbia Library Association 039
People's Archive, MLK Library
District of Columbia Library Association Records
1894-1997
People's Archive, MLK Library
District of Columbia Library Association
039
46 Boxes
Biographical / Historical
After a preliminary gathering at Columbian (now George Washington) University on June 6, 1894, 44 persons met on June 15 to establish the library Association of Washington City. The new organization's purpose interaction among librarians "and all interested in library work in Washington City and vicinity, and to further library interests in general." The first regular meeting was held on October 24, 1894, when members gathered in the Directors' room at Columbian University to hear the inaugural address by the first president, Librarian of Congress Ainsworth Rand Spofford, to describe the special features of their own libraries, and to form project committees. In March 1901 the name of the organization was changed to the District of Columbia Library Association. It became a chapter in the American Library Association on June 28, 1922 and was incorporated in the District of Columbia on February 25, 1927. The association was granted federal tax-exempt status under section 501 (c) (3) of the Internal Revenue Code on July 31, 1979.
A more complete history of the District of Columbia Library Association can be found in the book Capital Librarians: A History of the District of Columbia Library Association by John Y. Cole (Washington, DC: Library of Congress, 1994).
Custodial History
The papers of the Association were donated to Washingtoniana in the early 1930's. They were transferred to Catholic University from 1954 to 1973. These records were returned to the Washingtoniana Division in 1974. Materials have been donated by outgoing officers and other active DCLA members.
Scope and Contents
The papers of the District of Columbia Library Association consist of approximately 16 linear feet of material documenting the activities of this organization from its inception in 1894 to the present day. Material includes minutes, financial records, correspondence, handbooks, publicity materials, organization publications and photographs.
Libraries; Associations, institutions, etc; Librarians; Organizational Records; Photographs; Minutes (Records)
- Series 1: Minutes and Official Records
  Scope and Contents
  Includes minutes of meetings, President's Notebook (which include minutes of meetings, financial documents, correspondence and other administrative materials), financial records of the treasurer, reports and other documents from Interest Groups and Committees, material documenting Legislative Day activities and officers' handbooks.
  - Official Records, June 6 1894 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Official Records, November 21 1906 - December 11 1912 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bound Volumes of Minutes and List of Activities, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bound Volumes of Minutes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Executive board minutes, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - President's Notebook materials, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - President's Notebook materials, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - President's Notebook, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - President's Notebook, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - President's Notebook, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - President's Notebook, 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - President's Notebook, 1983-1984 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - President's Notebook, 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - President's Notebook, 1984-1985 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - President's Notebook and Guide to Officers, 1985-1986 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - President's Notebook, 1987-1988 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - President's Notebook, 1988-1990 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Minutes and Other Administrative Materials, 1989-1990 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1991-1993 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Annual Reports and Other Year-End Documents, 1991-1992 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Administrative Materials, 1991-1992 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Minutes and Other Administrative Materials, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and Other Materials, 1993-1994 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Materials, 1994-1995 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - President's Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Material from Board Minutes, 1994-1995 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Material from Board Minutes, 1995-1996 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Interest Groups and Committees Archives, Undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Interest Groups and Committees Awards Committee, Undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Interest Groups and Committees Children's and Young Adult Interest Group, Undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Interest Groups and Committees Government Documents Interest Group, Undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Interest Groups and Committees Reference Interest Group including Reference Group Round-up, Undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Interest Groups and Committees Elections Committee, Undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Interest Groups and Committees Preservation Interest Group, Undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Manual Drafting Committee Report, May 10 1965 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Manual for Officers and Committee Chairs, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Handbook, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Handbook, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Handbook, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Handbook, 1988-1989 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Handbook, 1989-1990 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Handbook, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Handbook, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Handbook, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Handbook, 1994-1995 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Handbook, 1995-1996 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Legislative Day, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Legislative Day, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Legislative Day, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Legislative Day, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Legislative Day, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Legislative Day, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - ALA Legislative Update "Handouts and Other Materials", 1985 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Library Committee-Bank Receipts and Statements, Undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Deposits at NS and T Bank, 1982-1985 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Deposits at NS and T Bank, 1982-1985 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Legislative Day Income and Expenditures; Financial Contributors and Other Financial, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Information, Undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Information, Undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Legislative Day Invitation to Reception and Other Brochures, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Legislative Day Invitation to Reception and Other Brochures, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Legislative Day Invitation and Other Brochures, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Legislative Day Letters/Memos /Other Correspondence, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Legislative Day Letters/Memos/Other Correspondence, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Legislative Day Letters/Memos/Other Correspondence and lists of Committee Members, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Legislative Day Letters/Memos/Other Correspondence, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Legislative Day Mailing Lists/Vendors/Sister Associations Contributor Status, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Legislative Day Mailing Lists/Vendors/Sister Associations Contributor Status, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Legislative Day Mailing Lists/Vendors/Sister Associations Contributor Status, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Legislative Day Photographs and Negatives, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Legislative Day Questions and Reports on Congressional Office Visits; Reports States, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Arizona to Georgia, Undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Legislative Day Reports on Congressional Office Visits Hawaii to North Carolina, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Legislative Day Reports on Congressional Office Visits Nebraska to West Virginia, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Legislative Day Responses to Invitation to Reception, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - OPM Standards, Undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - OMB Circular and FES OF Position Classification, Undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Legislative Day Expenses, Undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Legislative Day Corporations, Undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Legislative Day Income Associations, Undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Legislative Day Associations, Undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Legislative Day Final Report, Undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Legislative Day Financial Report, Undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Legislative Day Expenditures, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Legislative Day Photographs, 1996 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - DCLA Announcements, 1966-1974 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - DCLA Announcements, 1966-1974 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - DCLA Budget and Finance, 1969-1970 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - DCLA Budget and Finance, 1969-1970 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - DCLA Action (Pending) Treasurer, 1972-1974 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - DCLA Treasurer's Notes, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - DCLA Board Meeting Notes (Treasurer's Notes), 1972-1973 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - DCLA Board Meeting Notes (Treasurer's Notes), 1972-1973 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - DCLA Board Meeting Notes (Treasurer's Notes), 1973-1974 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - DCLA Board Meeting Notes (Treasurer's Notes), 1973-1974 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - DCLA Informational Materials Treasurer, 1972-1974 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - DCLA Board Meeting Notes, Undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - DCLA Instruction Information Treasurer, 1972-1974 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - DC Library Jobline COG (223-2272), 1973-74 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - DC Library Workshop Communications in the Library, Undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - DC Library Workshop, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - DC Library Workshop, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Joint Spring Workshop, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Joint Spring Workshop, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Joint Spring Workshop, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Joint Spring Workshop, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Joint Spring Workshop, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Joint Spring Workshop, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Spring Workshop Programs, 1978-1979 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - "We the People", 1984-1986 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - "We the People", 1984-1986 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Ledgers and Notes, 1960-1969 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Bank Statements, 1969-1970 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Check Ledger, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - DCLA Banks, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Bank Statements, 1970-1971 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Bills, 1970-1971 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Check Ledger, 1972-1973 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - DCLA Budget, 1972-1973, 1973-1974 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - DCLA Membership Renewals, 1972-1973 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1972-1974 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Bank Statements and Receipts, 1972-1974 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Bank Statements, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - DCLA Bills Paid, 1972-1973 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - DCLA Bills Paid, 1972-1973 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - DCLA Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Check Register, 1973-1974 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - DCLA Memberships, 1973-1974 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Bills Paid, 1973-1974 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Bills Paid, 1973-1974 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Bank Statements, 1974-75 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Bills Paid, 1974-1975 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Bills Paid, 1974-1975 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - DCLA Bank Statements and Other Materials, 1974-1975 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Membership, 1974-1975 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Membership, 1974-1975 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - DCLA Treasurer's Reports, 1974-1976 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1975-1978 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1975-1978 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Check Stubs, 1975-1977 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Membership, 1976-1978 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - DCLA Bills Paid, 1975-1976 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Bank Statements, 1975-1977 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - DCLA Census Workshop, 28096 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Bank Statements, 1976-1977 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Bills Paid, 1976-1977 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Bills Paid, 1976-1977 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Membership, 1977-1978 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Bank Statements, 1977-1978 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Billing, 1977-1978 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Saving Certificates, 1978-1980 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Invoices, 1978-1979 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Invoices, 1978-1979 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1978-1981 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Informatics, 1978-1979 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Income Tax Form, 1979 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Check Receipts, 1977-1979 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Balance Sheets, 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Check Ledger, 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Invoices, 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Invoices, 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Invoices, 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence and Invoices, 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Membership Lists, 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Membership, 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Balance Sheets, 1985-1986 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Budget, 1986-1987 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1986-1987 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Fund for Government Investors, 1986-1987 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Budget, 1987-1988 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1987-1988 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Fund for Government Investors, 1987-1988 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Budget, 1988-1989 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Check Register, 1988-1989 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1988-1989 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - 703 Miscellaneous Income, 1988-1989 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Budget, 1989-1990 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Signature Information, 1989-1990 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Membership Information, 1989-1990 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Income 703, 1989-1990 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Statements, 1989-1990 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1989-1990 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Budget, 1990-1992 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Perpetual CD, 1990-1992 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Budget, 1990-1991 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - American Security Bank Statements, 1990-1991 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Presstar, 1990-1991 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Signatures, 1990-1991 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Information and Bills, 1990-1991 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Management Interest Group, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Government Documents Interest Group, 1990-1991 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - American Security Bank Statements, 1991-1994 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - American Security Bank Statements, 1991-1994 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Presstar August-November, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Ads, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Membership Committee New Members Reception, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Membership Committee New Members Reception, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Planning Breakfast and Planning Lunch, June 1991, November 1991 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Banquet, May 1991 (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - ALA Councilor, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Children's and Young Adults Interest Group, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - Library Technology/Technical Services Interest Group, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Awards Committee, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - Contributions, 1991-1992 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - PSI, 1991-1992 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Membership, 1991-1992 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Expenses, 1991-1992 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Assistant Treasurer, 1991-1992 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Library Directory Project, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Banquet May, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Children's and Young Adult Interest Group, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Government Documents Interest Group, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Library Technology Interest Group, Undated (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Management Interest Group, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Genealogy Interest Group, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Technical Services Interest Group, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - DCLA Publicity Materials, Undated (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Treasurer's Report and Budget, 1992-1993 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - DCLA Paid Bills, 1993-1994 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - DCLA Paid Bills, 1993-1994 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - DCLA Paid Bills, 1993-1994 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Membership Brochures, 1994-1995 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Computer Disks Unknown Date, Undated (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Computer Disks, 1992-1993, 1993-1994 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Balances Sheets, 1967-1970 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Balances Sheets, 1970-1973 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Balance Sheets, 1973-1977 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Invoices, 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Invoices, 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Invoices, 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Fiscal Year Disbursements, 1977-1978, 1976-1977 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Receipts, 1978-1979 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Bank Statements, 1978-1979 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Balance Sheets, 1978-1979 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Receipts and Membership Lists, 1978-1979 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Balance Sheets, 1979-1980 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Tax Status- Articles of Incorporation, Undated (Box 28, Folder 13)
- Series 2: Publications
  Includes copies of publications produced by DCLA and DCLA officers. This includes copies of Inter-com, Clip and Quotes and DC Libraries.
  - Library Association of Washington City -Handbook With Notes on Libraries in Washington - Washington D.C., 1897 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Library Association of Washington City -Handbook With Notes on Libraries in Washington - Supplement - Washington D.C. (3 copies), 1898 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Library Association of Washington City -Handbook/Constitution/List of Members - Second Supplement - Washington D.C., 1990 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Library Association of Washington City -Handbook/Constitution/List of Members - Second Supplement - Washington D.C., 1990 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - District of Columbia Library Association Handbook, February 1904 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Library of Congress, Undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Government Printing Office, 1914 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Government Printing Office, 1914 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - District of Columbia Library Association- Handbook - Washington D.C. - District of Columbia Library Association, 1930 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - District of Columbia Library Association - Handbook 1934 - Washington D.C. - District of Columbia Library Association (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - D.C. Libraries - Handbook - Vol.7. No.3, April 1936 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - D.C. Libraries - Handbook - Vol.9 No.3, April 1938 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - D.C. Libraries - Handbook - Vol.9 No.3, April 1938 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - D.C. Libraries - Handbook of the District of Columbia Library Association -Supplement - Vol. 11 No.3, April 1940 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - D.C. Libraries - Handbook of the District of Columbia Library Association - Vol. 13 No. 3, July 1942 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - D.C. Libraries - Handbook of the District of Columbia Library Association - Vol.15 No.4 (2 copies; one hardbound), July 1944 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - D.C. Libraries - Handbook of the District of Columbia Library Association - Vol. 17 No. 4 (2 copies; one hardbound), July 1946 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - D.C. Libraries - Handbook of the District of Columbia Library Association - Vol.19 No. 4 (2 copies), July 1948 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - D.C. Libraries - Handbook of the District of Columbia Library Association - Vol. 21 No. 4 and Vol. 22 No.1 (3 copies), July 1950, October 1950 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - D.C. Libraries - Handbook of the District of Columbia Library Association - Vol.23 No. 3 (3 copies; one hardbound), July 1952 (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - District of Columbia Library Association - Handbook and Directory 1954 published by the Association with the cooperation of the Library of Congress - Washington D.C. (3 Copies) (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - D.C. Libraries - District of Columbia Library Association - Handbook and Directory - Vol.29, January 1958 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - D.C. Libraries - District of Columbia Library Association - Handbook and Directory 1960, October 1959 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - D.C. Libraries - District of Columbia Library Association - Handbook and Directory 1962 - Volume 32; Number 4, October 1961 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - D.C. Libraries - District of Columbia Library Association - Handbook and Directory 1964 - Volume 34; Number 4, October 1963 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - District of Columbia Library Association - Membership Directory, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - District of Columbia Library Association - Membership Directory, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - District of Columbia Library Association - Membership Directory, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence relating to publications, Undated (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - District of Columbia Library Association - Washington's Facilities for Training in Library Science - Washington D.C. (2 Copies), 1923 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - MLA and DCLA Joint Conference Program, 1926 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - George F. Bowerman - The New Biography - Washington D.C. - District of Columbia Library Association - 1929. A paper read by the Librarian of the Public Library before the Columbian Library Association, January 19 1929 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Eleanor Rossevelt - What Libraries Mean to the Nation: An Address given at the District of Columbia Library Association Dinner - April 1, 1936 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Ainsworth R. Spofford - What to Read. When you Read: How to Read: An Address to the Teachers of the Public Schools of Washington - October 20 1883 - Washington (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Brief and Specifications for Library Service in the Federal Government. Submitted to the Personnel Classification Board by the Committee of Government Librarians - Miles O. Price - Chairman. Washington DC: District of Columbia Library Association, 1923 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - DCLA Program, May 4 1937 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Speech by Helen Keller given at DCLA Meeting, 1942 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Program of the Sixth Convention of the Inter-American Bibliographical and Library Association in a joint meeting with DCLA, February 20 1943 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Inter-American Library Conference co-sponsored with Inter-American Bibliographical and Library Association/DCLA/DCSLA, March 30 1946 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Membership Brochures and Application Forms, Undated (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Membership Brochures and Application Forms, Undated (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Program Brochures, Undated (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Meeting Announcements and Brochures, Undated (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Clips and Quotes, November 1967 - May 1970 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Washington Area Library Directory floppy disk copies, 1992, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Washington Area Library Directory, Undated (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - DCLA Member Mailing Labels, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - DCLA Member Mailing Labels, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 28)
  - D.C. Libraries issues, Undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - D.C. Libraries issues, 1930-1970 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - D.C. Libraries issues, 1955-1970 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Inter-com, 1971-1983 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Inter-com, 1984-1994 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Inter-com, 1995-2003 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Publications, Bound Volumes, 1956-1989 (Box 39)
  - Publications, Intercom, and Index 1971-1991, 2003-2005 (Box 40)
- Series 3: Miscellaneous
  Includes material created to document the centennial of DCLA, photographs from DCLA events, publicity items and material generated by ALA.
  - Invitations to the Centennial Gala, Undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - John Y. Cole - Capital Libraries and Librarian: A Brief History of the District of Columbia Library Association. Washington: Library of Congress (4 copies), 1994 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Publicity for "Capital Libraries and Librarians", Undated (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Publicity for "Capital Libraries and Librarians", Undated (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Centennial Banquet program, Undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - "Centennial Times", Undated (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Centennial Public Relations, Undated (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Copies of photographs used in "Capital Libraries and Librarians", Undated (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Copies of photographs used in the traveling exhibit, Undated (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Photographs of the Capitol, Undated (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Grant Application to the DC Humanities Council, Undated (Box 41, Folder 11)